Guide to the Mark D. Weiser Papers, 1969-1999
Department of Special Collections
Mark D. Weiser Papers,
1969-1999
Special Collections M1069
Weiser, Mark D.
94 linear ft.
Stanford University. Libraries. Dept. of Special Collections and University Archives.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
The contents of the Business Plan series are restricted until June 2019.
Provenance
Gift of Victoria Reich, 1999 May.
Biography
Dr. Mark Weiser was the Chief Technologist at the Xerox Palo Alto Research Center (PARC). Weiser never received a bachelor's degree but earned his PhD in Computer and Communications Sciences from the University of Michigan (1979). Weiser was assistant and associate professor and associate chair in the Computer Science Department at the University of Maryland from 1979 to 1987, when he joined Xerox PARC as a member of the technical staff, then heading the Computer Science Laboratory for seven years. He started three companies. His over 75 technical publications are on such areas as the psychology of programming, program slicing, operating systems, programming environments, garbage collection, and technological ethics. Weiser's work since 1988 focused on Ubiquitous Computing, a program he initiated that envisions PC's being replaced with invisible computers embedded in everyday objects. He believed that this will lead to an era of "calm technology", in which technology, rather than panicking us, helps us focus on what is really important to us.
Mark Weiser was born on July 23, 1952 in Chicago, Illinois. Named Mark David Weiser after his father, David, he moved with his family to Mt. Carroll, Illinois when he was four years old. There he enjoyed a peaceful existence with his paper route, electronic projects, and garage band the Outsiders (not the Outsiders). At the age of fourteen he and his family moved to Ithaca, New York and after one year moved to Stony Brook, New York where he finished high school.
Weiser was also the drummer of the rock band Severe Tire Damage, the first live band on the Internet.
He died in May 1999 and is survived by his widow, Victoria Reich, and their two daughters, Nicole Reich-Weiser and Corinne Reich-Weiser.
Chronological Biography
1967 (First paid programming work, Chemistry Department, Cornell University)
1970-1975 Omnitext, Inc., Programmer, Ann Arbor, MI
1973-1976 Cerberus Inc., Co-founder and President, Ann Arbor, MI
1973-1976 Portable Information Systems, Ltd., Co-founder and Vice-President, Ann Arbor, MI
1974-1979 University of Michigan, Research Assistant and MTS Counselor
1975-1976 MIS International, Project Leader, Detroit, MI
1979-1987 University of Maryland Computer Science Department.
1979-1984 Assistant Professor, University of Maryland Computer Science Department.
1981-1984 Laboratory Director, University of Maryland Computer Science Department
1984-1987 Associate Professor, University of Maryland Computer Science Department
1986-1987 Associate Chairman, University of Maryland Computer Science Department
1987 May - 1999 June Xerox PARC.
1988 Nov. - 1994 Dec. Head of the Computer Science Laboratory; Principal Scientist since 1988.
1999 Chief Technologist, Xerox PARC.
Series Description and Container List
- Series 1. Correspondence
  This series is comprised primarily of letters, printouts of email, and facsimiles to and from professional colleagues in the computer industry. It also contains some letters and cards from friends and family members.
  - Correspondence - Incoming, 1969 - 1979 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Outgoing, 1979 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Incoming, 1980 - 1982 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence, 1986 Jan. - May (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence, 1986 June - Aug. (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence, 1986 Sept. - Dec. (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Incoming, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Outgoing, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Gates, Bill. Memo to executive staff re: Scientific American article by Mark Weiser, 1991 Aug. 28 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Incoming [1 of 2], 1992 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - Incoming [2 of 2], 1992 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - Outgoing [1 of 6], 1992 Jan. - June (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - Outgoing [2 of 6], 1992 Jan. - June (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Correspondence - Outgoing [3 of 6], 1992 Jan. - June (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Correspondence - Outgoing [4 of 6], 1992 Jan. - June (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Correspondence - Outgoing [5 of 6], 1992 Jan. - June (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - Outgoing [6 of 6], 1992 Jan. - June (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - Outgoing [1 of 6], 1992 July - Dec. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - Outgoing [2 of 6], 1992 July - Dec. (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - Outgoing [3 of 6], 1992 July - Dec. (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - Outgoing [4 of 6], 1992 July - Dec. (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - Outgoing [5 of 6], 1992 July - Dec. (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - Outgoing [6 of 6], 1992 July - Dec. (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - Miscellaneous [1 of 2], 1992 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - Miscellaneous [2 of 2], 1992 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - John White Expense reports, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - John White miscellaneous, 1992 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Mark Weiser incoming [1 of 3], 1993 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Mark Weiser incoming [2 of 3], 1993 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Mark Weiser incoming [3 of 3], 1993 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Mark Weiser outgoing [1 of 2], 1993 Jan. - Mar. (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Mark Weiser outgoing [2 of 2], 1993 Jan. - Mar. (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Mark Weiser outgoing, 1993 Apr. - June (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Mark Weiser outgoing [1 of 3], 1993 July - Sept. (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Mark Weiser outgoing [2 of 3], 1993 July - Sept. (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Mark Weiser outgoing [3 of 3], 1993 July - Sept. (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Mark Weiser outgoing, 1993 Oct. - Dec. (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Mark Weiser incoming [1 of 2], 1994 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Mark Weiser incoming [2 of 2], 1994 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Mark Weiser outgoing [1 of 4], 1994 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Mark Weiser outgoing [2 of 4], 1994 (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Mark Weiser outgoing [3 of 4], 1994 (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Mark Weiser outgoing [4 of 4], 1994 (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Mark Weiser incoming correspondence, 1995 (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Mark Weiser outgoing correspondence [1 of 2], 1995 (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Mark Weiser outgoing correspondence [2 of 2], 1995 (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - incoming, 1996 (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - outgoing [1 of 4], 1996 (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - outgoing [2 of 4], 1996 (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - outgoing [3 of 4], 1996 (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Correspondence - outgoing [4 of 4], 1996 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence - incoming, 1997 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence - outgoing [1 of 3], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Correspondence - outgoing [2 of 3], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - outgoing [3 of 3], 1997 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence - incoming [1 of 2], 1998 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence - incoming [2 of 2], 1998 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence - outgoing [1 of 3], 1998 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Correspondence - outgoing [2 of 3], 1998 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence - outgoing [3 of 3], 1998 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Correspondence - incoming, 1999 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Correspondence - outgoing, 1999 (Box 6, Folder 1a)
  - Faxes (Box 6, Folder 1b)
  - Weiser personal correspondence (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Correspondence, n.d. (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Cards [1 of 2] (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Cards [2 of 2] (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Postcards (Box 6, Folder 6)
- Series 2. Project files
  This series consists of correspondence, memomoranda, notes, and reports documenting projects on which Weiser was working or which people reporting to him were supervising. The vast majority of these projects were undertaken at Xerox PARC, but some files from his time at the University of Maryland are also included.
  - Project descriptions (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - 4.3 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - ADS PMC (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - ADS PMC meeting, 1999 Apr. 1 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Air Force AFOSR-80-0270 final report (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Air Force AFOSR new proposal: Minker / Weiser (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Air Force AFOSR: slides (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Answers to Questions (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - Apple Wireless (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - ARPA: National Science Foundation (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - ARPA GloMo (Box 6, Folder 17)
  - ATR (Box 6, Folder 18)
  - BMFO (Box 6, Folder 19)
  - CDI (Box 6, Folder 20)
  - Cedar (Box 6, Folder 21)
  - CER (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - CIC (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - CISCO Systems (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - CMSC 838c notes (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Corporate Innovation Council (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - CRT, 1997 (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - CRT staff meeting notes, 1998 Jan. 29 (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - CSTB - ITRD (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - CSTB meeting at Sun Microsystems in Mountain View [1 of 4], 1998 Feb. 9-10 (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - CSTB meeting at Sun Microsystems in Mountain View [2 of 4], 1998 Feb. 9-10 (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - CSTB meeting at Sun Microsystems in Mountain View [3 of 4], 1998 Feb. 9-10 (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - CSTB meeting at Sun Microsystems in Mountain View [4 of 4], 1998 Feb. 9-10 (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - CSTB meeting - Irvine, Calif. [1 of 3], 1998 June 8-9 (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - CSTB meeting - Irvine, Calif. [2 of 3], 1998 June 8-9 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - CSTB meeting - Irvine, Calif. [3 of 3], 1998 June 8-9 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - DARPA (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - DARPA (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - DARPA [1 of 8] (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - DARPA [2 of 8] (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - DARPA [3 of 8] (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - DARPA [4 of 8] (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - DARPA [5 of 8] (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - DARPA [6 of 8] (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - DARPA [7 of 8] (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - DARPA [8 of 8] (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - DARPA contract DABT63-91-C-0027, 1991 May 17 (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - DART (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Deciphering VP format (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Defense contract #DABT63-91-C-0027 (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Design proposals [1 of 2] (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Design proposals [2 of 2] (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Development of Communications Technology in Japan (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - DIBA (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Digital Document Company - Xerox, 1996 July (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Documentation in the Year 2000, 1996 Apr. 24 (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Document Research, 1996 Nov. (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Emerging Document Types [EDT] (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - EDT Council meeting, 1998 June - July (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - EDT meeting, 1997 Nov. 21 (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - EDT talk, 1997 Sept. 8 (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Electric Paperback (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Second EPE Working group. Report [1 of 4], 1978 Dec. 13 (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Second EPE Working group. Report [2 of 4], 1978 Dec. 13 (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Second EPE Working group. Report [3 of 4], 1978 Dec. 13 (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Second EPE Working group. Report [4 of 4], 1978 Dec. 13 (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Extreme User Interface Research Group - 1998 Accomplishments, 1999 plans, 1999 Jan. 5 (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Final reports (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Galaxy (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Gartner PC [Personal Computing] costs (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Gastinel Plan / Dragon (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - GC [Garbage Collection] [1 of 8] (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - GC [Garbage Collection] [2 of 8] (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - GC [Garbage Collection] [3 of 8] (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - GC [Garbage Collection] [4 of 8] (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - GC [Garbage Collection] [5 of 8] (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - GC [Garbage Collection] [6 of 8] (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - GC [Garbage Collection] [7 of 8] (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - GC [Garbage Collection] [8 of 8] (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - GER Product Strategy Workshop, 1999 Jan. 20-22 (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Gifford proposal (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Glyphs projects (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Government Contracting Overhead Model for PARC, 1998 Dec. 16 (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Haddon (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Homenet (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - IBM R6000 [1 of 3] (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - IBM R6000 [2 of 3] (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - IBM R6000 [3 of 3] (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Image Capable Printer (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Infrastructure for Ubiquitous Computing, 1992 June 8 (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Integration of PARC and ADSTC (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Interactive Process Assessment, 1997 (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Internet Document Services - private data, 1996 (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - IPRM Progress and plans, 1997 Jan. (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - IR (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - ISRG retreat (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - IT Professional Magazine (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - JAVA (Box 10, Folder 18)
  - Joint Intelligence (Box 10, Folder 19)
  - Killer Aps (Box 10, Folder 20)
  - Knowledge Software and Solutions (Box 10, Folder 21)
  - LIVE Board (Box 10, Folder 22)
  - Low-Power Computing [1 of 4] (Box 10, Folder 23)
  - Low-Power Computing [2 of 4] (Box 10, Folder 24)
  - Low-Power Computing [3 of 4] (Box 10, Folder 25)
  - Low-Power Computing [4 of 4] (Box 10, Folder 26)
  - Mach (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Marketing [1 of 4] (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Marketing [2 of 4] (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Marketing [3 of 4] (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Marketing [4 of 4] (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Marketing [1 of 3] (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Marketing [2 of 3] (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Marketing [3 of 3] (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - MEMS photos - slides (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - MEMS - Weiser - Process (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - MEMS - Weiser - design rules (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Meta-Protocols (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Microsoft Corporation ITGWeb CONFIDENTIAL, 1998 Apr. 1 (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - MindApps (Box 11, Folder 14)
  - Minder (Box 11, Folder 15)
  - Minder II (Box 11, Folder 16)
  - Minder photographs / tab photographs (Box 11, Folder 17)
  - Minder technical specs (Box 11, Folder 18)
  - MPad old information (Box 11, Folder 19)
  - MRP Survey, 1990 (Box 12, Folder 1)
  - Mudge file (Mark's office) (Box 12, Folder 2)
  - Mudge/Weiser Japan trip, 1992 (Box 12, Folder 3)
  - Nanocell (Box 12, Folder 4)
  - NCR Notepad (Box 12, Folder 5)
  - Network Video Technology (Box 12, Folder 6)
  - New PARC research in "Security" (Box 12, Folder 7)
  - OCT (Box 12, Folder 8)
  - OCT Talk (Box 12, Folder 9)
  - Olivetti (Box 12, Folder 10)
  - OMIKK Project Status / Chris Thompson, 1998 June 15 (Box 12, Folder 11)
  - PARC Monthly Management Meeting, 1998 July 27 (Box 12, Folder 12)
  - PARC Project Survey (Box 12, Folder 13)
  - PARC QTID objectives (Box 12, Folder 14)
  - PAST@PARC [1 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 15)
  - PAST@PARC [2 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 16)
  - PAST@PARC [3 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 17)
  - Patent Application (Box 12, Folder 18)
  - Patent Committee (Box 12, Folder 19)
  - PCR measurements (Box 12, Folder 20)
  - PDA (Box 12, Folder 21)
  - PDR [personal document reader] [1 of 5] (Box 12, Folder 22)
  - PDR [personal document reader] [2 of 5] (Box 12, Folder 23)
  - PDR [personal document reader] [3 of 5] (Box 12, Folder 24)
  - PDR [personal document reader] [4 of 5] (Box 12, Folder 25)
  - PDR [personal document reader] [5 of 5] (Box 12, Folder 26)
  - PDR [personal document reader] IP [1 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 27)
  - PDR [personal document reader] IP [2 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 28)
  - PDR [personal document reader] IP [3 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 29)
  - Personal Document Reader proposal, 1997 Oct. 7 (Box 12, Folder 30)
  - Portable Document Reader (Box 12, Folder 31)
  - PE2 [Programming Environments 2] [1 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 32)
  - PE2 [Programming Environments 2] [2 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 33)
  - PE2 [Programming Environments 2] [3 of 3] (Box 12, Folder 34)
  - Product Delivery Process (Box 13, Folder 1)
  - Projects at PARC (Box 13, Folder 2)
  - Reading Machines (Box 13, Folder 3)
  - Red Daedalus (Box 13, Folder 4)
  - Refalo Kyocera [1 of 2] (Box 13, Folder 5)
  - Refalo Kyocera [2 of 2] (Box 13, Folder 6)
  - Reno Library (Box 13, Folder 7)
  - SDSS - Senior Staff Theme meeting, 1998 Apr. 21 (Box 13, Folder 8)
  - Software patents / software [1 of 2] (Box 13, Folder 9)
  - Software patents / software [2 of 2] (Box 13, Folder 10)
  - SOSP - II slides (Box 13, Folder 11)
  - SOSP paper, 1991 (Box 13, Folder 12)
  - SOSP conference (Box 13, Folder 13)
  - SPARC System Software licensing, 1987 Sept. (Box 13, Folder 14)
  - Speculative TS (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - STD Remote Control (Box 13, Folder 16)
  - Steelcase [1 of 2] (Box 13, Folder 17)
  - Steelcase [2 of 2] (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - SUN HDTV, Northcutt (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Survey of PARC projects (Box 13, Folder 20)
  - Survey results (Box 13, Folder 21)
  - System 33 [1 of 2] (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - System 33 [2 of 2] (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - System 33 [1 of 2] (Box 13, Folder 24)
  - System 33 [2 of 2] (Box 13, Folder 25)
  - System 33 draft, 1988 June 16 (Box 13, Folder 26)
  - System 33 rewrite [1 of 2] (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - System 33 rewrite [2 of 2] (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Tacit, Inc. license of mobile computing IP (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Ubiquitous clippings [1 of 2] (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Ubiquitous clippings [2 of 2] (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Ubiquitous computing and activity theory / Robert John Skinner (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Voice Project (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Web performance (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Workscape, 1999 Apr. 4 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - X-Pad (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - XR&T (Box 14, Folder 9)
- Series 3. Business plans
  This series contains business plans, corporate strategies, analysis of potential markets, and other documents generated by Mark Weiser and member of Xerox PARC in their attempts to strategize the marketing of new technologies being developed at Xerox PARC.
  - Strategic plans / strategy [1 of 3] (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Strategic plans / strategy [2 of 3] (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Strategic plans / strategy [3 of 3] (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Strategic plan for the role of human language technology in the creation, processing, and sharing of information and knowledge, 1998 Nov. 27 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Architecture & document servers (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Burlap (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Business plans [1 of 4] (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Business plans [2 of 4] (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Business plans [3 of 4] (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Business plans [4 of 4] (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - Corporate strategies (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - DocuMart Trusted Printer Considerations (Box 15, Folder 3)
  - The document company story, 1997 Sept. 23 (Box 15, Folder 4)
  - Document viewing business case (Box 15, Folder 5)
  - DynaPad Business Plan, 1986 Feb. 27 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - Fluke software - contract (Box 15, Folder 7)
  - Fuji XEROX - XEROX license (Box 15, Folder 8)
  - FXPAL (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - iReady Corporation Business plan, 1995 Dec. 10 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - iReady Corp., 1997 (Box 15, Folder 11)
  - LANL / XRX [Los Alamos National Laboratories / Xerox] (Box 15, Folder 12)
  - Los Alamos / Sandia Laboratories [1 of 6], 1997 Feb. 19-21 (Box 15, Folder 13)
  - Los Alamos / Sandia Laboratories [2 of 6], 1997 Feb. 19-21 (Box 15, Folder 14)
  - Los Alamos / Sandia Laboratories [3 of 6], 1997 Feb. 19-21 (Box 16, Folder 1)
  - Los Alamos / Sandia Laboratories [4 of 6], 1997 Feb. 19-21 (Box 16, Folder 2)
  - Los Alamos / Sandia Laboratories [5 of 6], 1997 Feb. 19-21 (Box 16, Folder 3)
  - Los Alamos / Sandia Laboratories [6 of 6], 1997 Feb. 19-21 (Box 16, Folder 4)
  - Microsoft Window 98 (Box 16, Folder 5)
  - CSL Private notes, 1991 (Box 16, Folder 6)
  - Personal notes (Box 16, Folder 7)
  - Stephanie's business notes [1 of 2] (Box 16, Folder 8)
  - Stephanie's business notes [2 of 2] (Box 16, Folder 9)
  - Object products: business plans, 1993 Oct. 14 (Box 16, Folder 10)
  - Strategic plans (Box 16, Folder 11)
  - Tacit business plan, 1995 Nov. 13 (Box 16, Folder 12)
  - Time Keeper (Box 16, Folder 13)
  - ViewPoint Technologies, Inc. Business plan for initial funding, 1992 Aug. 6 (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Xerox Internet division (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Xerox - Spectra Diode Laboratories agreement, 1983 Mar. 31 (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Xerox & Tacit (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Businesses: Product design (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Businesses: Software / engineering (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Businesses: Recruiting (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Businesses: Advertising / marketing / business development (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Businesses: Banking (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Businesses: Business plan list (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Businesses: Business plan [Tacit], 1995 Dec. 31 (Box 17, Folder 11)
  - Businesses: Business plan [Tacit], 1995 Nov. 13 (Box 17, Folder 12)
  - Businesses: Business plan [Tacit], 1995 Oct. 22 (Box 17, Folder 13)
  - Confidential disclosure agreements: CDA for Stanford (Box 17, Folder 14)
  - Confidential disclosure agreements: XEROX confidential disclosure agreements (Box 17, Folder 15)
- Series 4. Patents / Intellectual Property files
  This series contains patent applications, contracts, agreements, correspondence, and electronic mail printouts documenting Xerox PARC's efforts to defend the intellectual property rights deriving from inventions developed at Xerox PARC.
  - Patent (Box 18, Folder 1)
  - Intellectual property filings 1998 (Box 18, Folder 2)
  - MIT: The Media Laboratory 1998 (Box 18, Folder 3)
  - Patent application - Attorney docket no. D/93335 1993 Dec. 3 (Box 18, Folder 4)
  - Patent application - Attorney docket no. D/93336 1993 Dec. 3 (Box 18, Folder 5)
  - Patent application - Attorney docket no. D/93337 1993 Dec. 3 (Box 18, Folder 6)
  - Patents - internal memo 1994 Apr. 22 (Box 18, Folder 7)
  - Patents - Method & System for reclaiming unreferenced computer memory space 1992 Dec. 10 (Box 18, Folder 8)
  - Patents - Pad Pals (Box 18, Folder 9)
  - Patents - Personal privacy for mobile users in distributed computing environments (Box 18, Folder 10)
  - Patents - RAMDoubler (Box 18, Folder 11)
  - Patents - Stylus Alphabets 1992 Nov. 17 (Box 18, Folder 12)
  - Proposals for intellectual property transfer (Box 18, Folder 13)
  - Xerox invention proposals to be submitted n.d. Sept. 1, Nov. 1 (Box 18, Folder 14)
  - Xerox invention proposal - Second generation electric paper 1994 Apr. 7 (Box 18, Folder 15)
  - Xerox invention proposal 1994 Apr. 22 (Box 18, Folder 16)
  - Xerox invention proposal - Sharp Threshold electric paper 1994 May 5 (Box 18, Folder 17)
  - Xerox invention proposal - Weakly-consistent replicated data model - Confidential 1994 Sept. 14 (Box 18, Folder 18)
  - Summary of IP status and IP submissions for 1994 PARC IP's as of Sept. 30, 1994 1994 Oct. 5 (Box 18, Folder 19)
  - Xerox invention proposal / David L. Hecht 1996 Dec. 31 (Box 18, Folder 20)
  - Xerox invention proposal - Wireless microphones / David Biegelsen (Box 18, Folder 21)
  - Minder patent status (Box 18, Folder 22)
  - Dynamic Predictive keyboard Patent no. 5,128,672 1992 July 7 (Box 18, Folder 23)
  - Handoff method and apparatus for Mobile Wireless Workstation Patent no. 5,181,200 1993 Jan. 19 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Encoding-format-desensitized methods and means for interchanging electronic document appearances. Patent no., 5,210,824, 1993 May 11 (Box 18, Folder 24)
  - Medium access protocol for wireless LANs Patent no. 5,231,634 1993 July 27 (Box 18, Folder 25)
  - Method of testing programs and compiler and program testing tool for the method Patent no. 5,255,385 1993 Oct. 19 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Method and system for reclaiming unreferenced computer memory space Patent no. 5,321,834 1994 June 14 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Method and system for the dynamic slection, allocation, and arbitration of control between devices within a region Patent no. 5,485,634 1996 Jan. 16 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Selective delivery of electronic messages in a multiple computer system based on context and environment of a user Patent no. 5,493,692 1996 Feb. 20 (Box 18, Folder 27)